# Farhaan Mohammad Sa'ad Beeharry

Port Louis, Mauritius, 11611
+230 5707 6881 || contact@farhaan.info || Online Portfolio at farhaan.info linkedin.com/in/farhaan-beeharry

# **Personal Profile**

I am a diligent Software Engineer at Information Technology ELCA Ltd with over 1 year of experience in commercial application development and a recent graduate of BSc Computer Science (Systems Engineering) from Middlesex University Mauritius with First Class Honours. I have experience in improving and updating existing projects, as well as developing new software functionalities. I am a creative and responsible professional with excellent problem-solving skills looking for a position as a Software Engineer.

# **Work Experience**

## Associate Software Engineer, August 2021 to Present

Information Technology ELCA Ltd, Saint-Pierre, Mauritius

- Working on 3rd Party Projects using Angular and Java.
- Utilised crucial design software skills to assist with projects.
- Effective changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.

# Mobile Application Developer (Internship), May 2020 to August 2020

Navigation and Geocoding Technologies Ltd, Port-Louis, Mauritius

- Mobile Development of "Naveo Driver" Application using Flutter.
- Worked to solve complex problems using the latest Mobile Technologies.
- Writing source codes and making changes according to client's requests.

## Trainee Network Engineer (Internship), May 2019 to August 2019

Secure Services Mauritius Ltd, Port-Louis, Mauritius

- Shadow Network Engineers in deploying and configuring of network devices.
- Ensured network security by developing and configuring network access.
- Analysed network components to identify beneficial improvements.

# **Education**

BSc Computer Science (Systems Engineering) - First Class, 2018 to 2021

Middlesex University Mauritius, Flic-en-Flac, Mauritius

#### Cambridge Higher School Certificate - A Level, 2017

Royal College Curepipe, Curepipe, Mauritius

#### Cambridge School Certificate - O Level, 2014

Royal College Curepipe, Curepipe, Mauritius

## **Certificates**

# **Financial Services Commission, December 2022**

Third prize winner - Mobile App Design Competition

## **ELCAdemy, February 2022**

Information Technology ELCA Ltd, Mauritius - Angular and Java Training

# **UoM Online Inter-University TechWar, March 2021**

Second prize winner - Crackathon Challenge

#### DigiCup 2020 - Digital Solution Challenge, November 2020

Second prize winner - Mobile Application - Flutter

# Introduction to Mechatronics - Using the Arduino Board, 2020

School of Electronics, Mauritius

#### Introduction to Programming Skills, 2017

RRJ Learning Centre, Mauritius

# Introduction to IT - 2, 2015

RRJ Learning Centre, Mauritius

# Australian Mathematics Competition (Yearly), 2010 to 2015

Royal College Curepipe, Mauritius (Organised by Australian Mathematics Trust, Australia)

# Technical Skills

- Web development: HTML/CSS, Angular, JavaScript and TypeScript
- Mobile application development: Flutter (iOS and Android)
- Programming languages: Java (Spring / Spring Boot), Dart, PHP, Python and SQL
- Tools: Jira, Git, Confluence, IntelliJ and Visual Studio Code

# **Professional Skills**

- Ability to multitask Juggling different work activities and shifting attention between tasks
- Creativity Introducing new and innovative ideas with the use of imagination and originality
- Effective time management Effective coordination of tasks and activities
- Fast learner Pick up technical skills fast, tracking development and quick adaptability
- **Problem solving** Ability to handle problems, determine the issue and resolve

## **Projects / Relevant Experience**

- Youth in Action DigiCup 2020 Competition project (Second prize winner) Flutter
- Flame Detection System Arduino and xBee
- Automatic Irrigation System Arduino, Flutter and Firebase
- Candidate Assessment System Angular and Java (Spring / Spring Boot)

# **Extra-curricular Activities**

#### **Event Organiser, October 2019 to June 2021**

LaunchTech (Student Society), Middlesex University Mauritius, Flic-en-Flac, Mauritius

# References Available Upon Request